Education, School of; Records ua650
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
School of Education Records1927-1988
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
State University of New York at Albany. School of Education
ua650
9.34 cubic ft.
The School of Education has its origins as the academic unit of the State Normal School in 1844. It remained a core part of the curriculum of the State College for Teachers (1914-1959) and continued after the 1960s as an academic school within a large public research university.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Web Archives
Administrative History
The School of Education at the State University of New York at Albany was created by an act of the New York State Legislature on May 7, 1844, as the Albany Normal School and modeled on l'Ecole Normale SupĂŠrieure in France. Its mission was to educate and train school teachers in the science of education and the art of teaching so that they might take up positions in the schools of both New York State and the rest of the United States. The Albany Normal School opened its doors on December 18, 1844, and started preparing teachers for the state's secondary schools. It offered a two-year teacher preparatory program. The Albany Normal School was the first normal school in the State of New York and the third in the United States. Its first year of funding included a $9,600 subsidy from the state's Literature Fund and the promise of $10,000 annually for the first five years. The Albany Normal School's first class had 29 students.
In 1905, the mission of the School of Education was expanded to preparing not only secondary school teachers, but also normal school ones. In 1906, graduate study commenced with the introduction of a one-year curriculum of post-baccalaureate study that led to a degree of Bachelor of Pedagogy. The school's two-year program was offered for the last time in 1908. In 1913, master's degree programs were added. In 1960, a doctoral degree in Educational Administration was added to the professional education courses as well as a program leading to a doctorate of philosophy. As the School of Education at the State University of New York at Albany grew, its mission grew in scope to include not only the education of classroom teachers, but also of the leaders who have shaped the nature of learning in the 20th and 21st centuries.
Since 1962, the School of Education has grown in size and scope. Its current mission is to foster enhanced learning and human development as well as to advance knowledge concerning the full spectrum of challenges in learning development, behavior, and adaptation. In order to achieve this, the School of Education offers many different academic programs taught by a large and diverse faculty. Currently, the school has four departments: Educational Administration Policy, Educational and Counseling Psychology, Educational Theory and Practice, and Reading. As of 2006, the School of Education had approximately 1400 graduate students, 1400 undergraduate students, 500 undergraduate minors, 95 part-time faculty, 65 full-time faculty, 30 master and Certificate for Advanced Studies programs, 6 doctoral programs, and two online programs.
Deans
1845-1849 David P. Page
1849-1852 George R. Perkins
1852-1857 Samuel B. Woolworth
1857-1865 David H. Cochran
1865-1867 Oliver C. Arey
1867 Samuel B. Woolworth
1867-1883 Joseph Alden
1883-1890 Edward P. Waterbury
1890-1906 William J. Milne
1906-1913 William J. Aspinwall
1913-1916 Leonard A. Blue
1916-1918 none
1918-1924 Harlan H. Horner
1924-1934 William H. Metzler
1934-1941 Milton G. Nelson
1941-1943 John M. Sayles
1943-1949 Robert W. Frederick
1949-1950 Robert W. Frederick/Milton C. Olson
1950-1951 Milton C. Olson /James A. Hicks
1951-1954 Milton C. Olson/Don A. Orton
1954-1959 Milton C. Olson/Edwin P. Adkins
1959-1960 Milton C. Olson/Edwin P. Adkins/John R. Tibbetts
1960-1962 Milton C. Olson/Edwin P. Adkins
1962-1963 Milton C. Olson/Edwin P. Adkins/Irving A. Vershoor
1963-1974 Randolph S. Gardiner
1974-1979 Gilbert D. Moore
1979-1992 Robert H. Koff
1992-2000 James T. Fleming
2000-2002 Ralph W. Harbison
2002-present Susan D. Phillips
Scope and Contents
This collection documents the organization, evolution, scope, thinking, activities and programs of the School of Education over a period of about seven decades. The earliest items date from about 1927, but continuous records start about 1960 and continue through 1988 with the largest portion of the records from the 1960s-1980s. There are no records in this collection that date from the founding of the School of Education or from the early years of its operation.
Topics which are extensively documented in this collection include adult basic education, Albany Public Schools, Argentine Nationals Program, the Bennington Project, counseling centers, the Doctor of Arts Program, the Doctor of Education Program, educational research training, educational television, education of the disadvantaged, the Experimental College, the Milne School, the National Defense Education Act, the Peace Corps training program in India, the Regional Education Laboratory, special education, summer institutes, Teaching English as a Second Language, the Two-Year College Consortium, and workshops.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized as follows:
.
Series arrangement statement: SUNY will complete.
Acquisition Information
All items in this manuscript group were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, in June 1988.
Related Materials
Several collections in the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives provide further information on education and policy issues that were of concern to the faculty, staff and students of the School of Education. For complete listings of related collections, consult the subject guides for University at Albany, SUNY Administrative Records and Education. Of particular note are the records of the Capital Area School Development Association (APAP-065), the Educational Opportunity Center (UA-560), the Educational Communications Center (UA-570), Department of English (UA-603), and the National Research Center on English Learning and Achievement (CELA) (UA-680.03).
Access
Access to student material in Box 1 and Box 2 of Series 3 is restricted. Series 1 and Series 2 are unrestricted. Consult a staff member for details.
Education; Education -- Study and teaching -- New York (State); Universities and colleges -- Accreditation.; Web Archives; UAlbany Schools & Colleges; State University of New York at Albany. School of Education..
- Administrative Files, 1953-1985; 1; 3 cubic ft.
  Scope and Contents
  This series consists of materials relating directly to the operations of the School of Education, and to some of its faculty and staff. There is one folder of records concerning the New York State Citizen Committee for the Public Schools dating from 1953, but most of the series date from the 1960s-1980s. The records of the activities and programs committees and minutes of the Dean's meetings are to be found here as are records pertaining to cabinet meeting notes, department chairs, and the minutes of faculty meetings. Other items found in this series include budget materials, by-laws, general correspondence, grants, memoranda, long-range planning, activities outside the university and teaching load statistics.
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - Academic Affairs Council, 1969-1972 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 1)
  - Accreditation, 1974 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 2)
  - Admissions, 1964-1978 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 3)
  - Advanced Program Committee, 1967-1969 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 4)
  - Advisory Council, 1970 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 5)
  - Advisory Council, 1971 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 6)
  - Advisory Council, 1972-1973 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 7)
  - Advisory Council, Special Story, 1972 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 8)
  - Allocation of Spaces, Problems, Requests, Location Needs, 1963-1968 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 9)
  - Alumni Activities, Undated (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 10)
  - Awards, 1969-1984 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 11)
  - Annual Report of Teacher Education Committee, 1974 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 12)
  - Benezet, Louis T., 1970-1973 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 13)
  - Budgets, 1965-1968 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 14)
  - By-laws, 1971-1972 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 15)
  - Cabinet Meeting and Notes, 1966 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 16)
  - Calendar, 1971 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 17)
  - Campus Dedication Committee, 1967 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 18)
  - Collins, Evan, 1962-1969 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 19)
  - Committee On Education Policies, 1963-1966 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, 1959-1972 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 21)
  - Councils and Committees, 1970-1977 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 22)
  - Curriculum Committee, 1952-1968 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 23)
  - Deans Meetings, 1971-1975 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 24)
  - Deans Meetings, 1976 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 25)
  - Deans and Directors Meetings, 1970-1971 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 26)
  - Department Chairpersons, 1965-1972 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 27)
  - Department Chairpersons, 1965-1972 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 28)
  - Department Chairpersons, 1972-1973 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 29)
  - Department of Off-Campus Supervision, 1975 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 30)
  - Departmental Counselors for Education Employment, 1974-1975 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 31)
  - Departments and Dean's Office, 1974 Fall-1978 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 32)
  - Droessler, Earl, Vice President for Research, Correspondence, 1966-1971 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 33)
  - Education Certifications, 1970-1971 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 34)
  - Education Societies, 1963-1966 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 35)
  - Enrollments Figures, 1965-1980 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 36)
  - Equal Opportunity Advisory Committee, 1970-1971 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 37)
  - Faculty, 1964-1976 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 38)
  - Faculty Meetings, 1965-1975 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 39)
  - Fellowship Assistantship, Undated (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 40)
  - Fiser, Webb, Correspondence, 1965-1968 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 1)
  - Flinton, Edgar, Dean of Graduate Studies, 1961-1971 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 2)
  - Goals and Priorities for Action, 1979-1982 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 3)
  - Graduate Committee, 1956-1957 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 4)
  - Graduate Outreach, 1985 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 5)
  - Graduate School of Public Affairs Alumni Association, 1985 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 6)
  - Graduation, 1972-1973 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 7)
  - Grants, 1970-1973 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 8)
  - Grants, 1965-1969 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 9)
  - Grants, 1966 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 10)
  - Grants, 1965-1968 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 11)
  - Grants, 1965-1968 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 12)
  - Grants, 1968-1971 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 13)
  - Grants, 1968-1971 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 14)
  - Higher Education Act, 1966-1967 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 15)
  - Kuusisto, Allan, Correspondence, 1968-1970 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 16)
  - Long-Range Planning, 1967-1972 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 17)
  - Mathews, Elmer, Dean, 1967-1973 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 18)
  - Memoranda, 1961-1975 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 19)
  - Memoranda, 1972 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 20)
  - Memoranda, 1965-1973 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 21)
  - Memoranda, 1965-1973 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 1)
  - Memoranda, 1965-1973 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 2)
  - Memoranda, 1965-1973 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 3)
  - Memoranda, 1963-1973 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 4)
  - Memoranda, 1962 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 5)
  - Memoranda, 1968-1971 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 6)
  - Memoranda, 1968-1971 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 7)
  - Memoranda, 1969-1973 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 8)
  - Memoranda, 1960-1973 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 9)
  - Middle States Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools, 1964 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 10)
  - Minutes, 1976 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 11)
  - New Campus, 1963-1967 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 12)
  - New Faculty Members, 1971-1974 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 13)
  - New Telephones Number, 1966 August 3 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 14)
  - New York State Citizen Committee For Public Schools, 1953 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 15)
  - Office Listing of School of Education, 1961-1962 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 16)
  - Olson, Milton, 1968-1970 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 17)
  - O'Reilly, Charles, Undated (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 18)
  - Organization, 1969-1974 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 19)
  - Outside University, 1967-1971 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 20)
  - Outside University, 1967-1971 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 21)
  - Outside University, 1967-1971 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 22)
  - Outside University, 1967-1971 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 23)
  - Outside University, 1967-1971 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 24)
  - Periodical Report For School of Education Topics, 1976 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 25)
  - Recognition Night, 1973 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 26)
  - Recruitment, 1969-1973 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 27)
  - Register's Office, 1968-1972 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 28)
  - Reorganization of the School of Education, 1974-1975 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 29)
  - Resource Allocation, Undated (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 30)
  - Retirements, 1975-1984 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 31)
  - Schedules, 1968-1973 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 32)
  - Scholarship, 1969 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 33)
  - Search Committee, Dean of Education, 1973 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 34)
  - Senate Council On Promotions, 1970 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 35)
  - Senate Meeting Reports, 1972 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 36)
  - Student Guidelines, 1964-1965 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 37)
  - A Student's Guide To the SUNYA Campus, 05/1974 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 38)
  - Student of SUNYA Graduates, 1968-1970 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 39)
  - Teacher Education Program Enrollments, 1972 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 40)
  - Teaching Load Statistics, 1955-1971 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 41)
  - Teaching Load Statistics, 1969-1970 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 42)
  - Urban Affairs Committee, 1972 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 43)
  - University Athletics Council, 1968 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 44)
  - Wakin, Bertha, 1973 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 45)
- Activities and Programs, 1927-1988; 2; 3 cubic ft.
  This series contains materials relating directly to the activities and programs of the School of Education. Topics of interest include administrators and in-service education, adult basic education, Albany Public Schools, the Argentine Nationals Programs, the Behavior Research Program, the Bennington Project, Black Studies, the Center for Executive Development, co-operative community college programs, courses, curricula, the Doctor of Arts Program, the Doctor of Education Program, educational administration, educational media, educational research, the Experimental College, the Milne School, National Defense Education Act, Peace Corps training program in India, the Regional Education Laboratory, reading teachers, school psychology, special education, summer institutes, training of teachers, the Training Program for Subject Supervisors, the Two-Year College Consortium, vocational rehabilitation, and workshops.
  - Administrators and In-service Education, 1968 (Box 1 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 1)
  - Educational Media, 1968-1979 (Box 1 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 2)
  - Adult Basic Education, 1966-1969 (Box 1 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 3)
  - Adult Basic Education, 1969-1970 (Box 1 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 4)
  - Albany Public Schools, 1966 (Box 1 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 5)
  - Application of Selected Media of Instruction to General Education, 1970 (Box 1 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 6)
  - Argentine Nationals Program, 1969 (Box 1 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 7)
  - Behavioral Research Program, 1964-1971 (Box 1 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 8)
  - A Bilingual Education Project, 1971-1972 (Box 1 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 9)
  - Bennington Project Ford Foundation, 1964-1966 (Box 1 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 10)
  - Black Studies, 1969 (Box 1 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 11)
  - Campus Academic Plan, 1965 (Box 1 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 12)
  - CASDA, 1970 (Box 1 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 13)
  - Center For Executive Development, 1963-1969 (Box 1 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 14)
  - Center For Training Urban Teachers, 1968-1969 (Box 1 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 15)
  - Child Research and Study Center, 1974-1975 (Box 1 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 16)
  - Classical Association of the Empire State, 1971-1974 (Box 1 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 17)
  - College Counseling, 1969-1973 (Box 1 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 18)
  - Colloquia, 1978-1984 (Box 1 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 19)
  - The Community College (Institute), 1972-1974 (Box 1 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 20)
  - Comparative Education Society, 1968 (Box 1 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 21)
  - Cooperative Community College Programs, 1967 (Box 1 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 22)
  - Counseling Centers, 1961-1969 (Box 1 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 23)
  - Courses, 1948-1959 (Box 1 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 24)
  - Courses, 1967-1985 (Box 1 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 25)
  - Criteria and the Educational of Educational Programs, 1974 (Box 1 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 26)
  - The Cross-Cultural Measurement of Values, 1967 (Box 1 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 27)
  - Curriculum, 1962-1972 (Box 1 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 28)
  - Curriculum Laboratory, 1970 September (Box 1 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 29)
  - Department of Business Education, 1968-1980 (Box 1 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 30)
  - Department of Counseling Psychology, 1988 (Box 1 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 31)
  - Department of Program Development and Evaluation, 1988 (Box 1 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 32)
  - Desegregation, 1968 (Box 1 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 33)
  - Doctor of Arts Program, 1971 (Box 1 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 34)
  - Doctoral Degree in Education Degree, 1952-1974 (Box 1 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 35)
  - Doctor of Psychology Program, 1979 (Box 1 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 36)
  - Education Day, 1967 (Box 1 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 37)
  - Educational Administration, 1961 (Box 1 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 38)
  - Educational Communication Center: Allocation an Understanding of the Drug, 1976 (Box 1 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 39)
  - Educational Researchers Training, 1966-1968 (Box 1 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 40)
  - Educational Researchers Training, 1966-1969 (Box 1 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 41)
  - Educational Television, 1960 (Box 1 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 42)
  - Education of the Disadvantaged, Undated (Box 1 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 43)
  - Education of the Disadvantaged, 1972 (Box 1 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 44)
  - Education of the Disadvantaged: Abe Bibliography, 1972 (Box 1 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 45)
  - Education of the Disadvantaged, Workshop for Instructor of Teachers, 1967 July 5-1967 July 14 (Box 1 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 46)
  - Environment Preference Schedule, 1974 (Box 1 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 47)
  - Experimental College, 1969 (Box 1 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 48)
  - Foundations of Education Graduate Programs, 1974 (Box 1 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 49)
  - Gardner, Randolph S., Resignation as Dean, 1972 (Box 1 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 50)
  - Graduate Studies, 1966-1971 (Box 1 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 51)
  - Graduate Survey, 1976 (Box 1 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 52)
  - History of Education Society, 1969 (Box 1 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 53)
  - Innovative Education in College and Community, 1970 January 22 (Box 1 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 54)
  - Institute for Development of Educational Activities, 1967 (Box 1 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 55)
  - Institute for Advanced Study For Media Specialists, 1966 August 22 (Box 2 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 1)
  - Institute for Self-Paced Instructional Strategies: Preparation of a Learning Activity Package, 1972 (Box 2 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 2)
  - Instructional Leadership, Undated (Box 2 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 3)
  - International Fire Administration Institute, Undated (Box 2 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 4)
  - International Programs, 1977 (Box 2 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 5)
  - Internship, 1964-1965 (Box 2 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 6)
  - Lectures in Education, Undated (Box 2 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 7)
  - Marist College, 1968 (Box 2 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 8)
  - Milne School, 1924-1979 (Box 2 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 9)
  - Milne School, 1924-1979 (Box 2 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 10)
  - Milne School, 1924-1979 (Box 2 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 11)
  - Music Education, 1969-1970 (Box 2 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 12)
  - National Center for Educational Research and Development, 1972-1973 (Box 2 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 13)
  - National Education Finance Project, 1969 (Box 2 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 14)
  - National Teacher Exams, 1965-1966 (Box 2 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 15)
  - National Teacher Corps, 1966 (Box 2 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 16)
  - NDEA, 1966-1968 (Box 2 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 17)
  - NDEA, 1966-1970 (Box 2 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 18)
  - NDEA, 1966-1970 (Box 2 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 19)
  - NDEA Fellowship Programs, 1966 (Box 2 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 20)
  - New Office of Business Education Learning, 1969 (Box 2 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 21)
  - New York State Committee of English Educators, 1969 (Box 2 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 22)
  - One Hundred and Fortieth Anniversary, 1984 (Box 2 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 23)
  - Power, Policy and Education: Studies in Development, 1968 (Box 2 (2-Activities and Programs), Folder 24)